Jacques Seligmann & Co.
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Germain Seligman's Personal Papers, 1882, circa 1905-1984, Series 12:; (Boxes 422-459; 17 linear feet)
  - War Files, 1913-1960, undated, 12.4:
    - Awards: Certificates and Service Records, 1913-1960, undated (Box 449, Folder 4)
    - Awards: Correspondence, 1919-1960 (Box 449, Folder 5)
    - Awards: Printed Material, 1915-1919, (not scanned) (Box 449, Folder 6)
    - Awards: Printed Material, 1920-1960, (not scanned) (Box 449, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Framed Letter to André Mare, 1915 (Box 449, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: French Consulate, 1933-1962 (Box 449, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Military Commission Application, 1939, 1941-1944, undated (Box 449, Folder 10)
  - Personal Financial Files, 1932-1984, undated, 12.5:
    Records in this subseries chronicle Germain Seligman's personal financial affairs and include records of taxes and investments. Correspondence with a Madrid bank in 1945-1957 includes documentation of frozen assets that Germain eventually liquidated.
    Material is arranged by subject and is chronological within folders. This series has not been scanned.
    - Bank Accounts, 1954-1976, (5 folders; not scanned) (Box 450, Folder 1-5)
    - Business and Personal Expense Journal, 1963-1967, (not scanned) (Box 450, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Compania de las Marismas, Spain, 1945-1957, undated, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 451, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence: J. Legrain, 1947-1961, undated, (not scanned) (Box 451, Folder 3)
    - Donations (1983), 1978-1984, (not scanned) (Box 451, Folder 4)
    - Insurance Papers, 1956-1978, undated, (not scanned) (Box 451, Folder 5)
    - Investment Journal, 1932-1937, (not scanned) (Box 451, Folder 6)
    - Investment Journal, 1943-1945, (not scanned) (Box 451, Folder 7)
    - Investment Journal, 1966-1974, (not scanned) (Box 451, Folder 8)
    - Investment Journal, 1975-1978, (not scanned) (Box 452, Folder 1)
    - Investment Reports and Statements, 1944-1978, (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 452, Folder 2-4)
    - Miscellaneous Financial Notes, undated, (not scanned) (Box 452, Folder 5)
    - Federal Income Taxes, 1941-1971, (4 folders; not scanned) (Box 452, Folder 6-9)
    - New York City Income Taxes, 1966-1969, (not scanned) (Box 453, Folder 1)
    - New York State Income Taxes, 1948-1971, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 453, Folder 2-3)
    - Tax Calculations, 1970-1975, (not scanned) (Box 453, Folder 4)
    - Tax Deductible Expenses, 1938-1968, (5 folders; not scanned) (Box 453, Folder 5-9)
    - Tax Deductible Expenses, 1969-1972, (7 folders; not scanned) (Box 454, Folder 1-7)
    - Tax Deductible Expenses, 1972-1974, (5 folders; not scanned) (Box 455, Folder 1-5)
    - Tax Deductible Expenses, 1975-1977, (4 folders; not scanned) (Box 456, Folder 1-4)
    - Tax Deductible Investments, 1975-1977, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 456, Folder 5-6)
  - Miscellaneous Files, 1882, 1936-1979, 12.6:
    Material found here relates primarily to research projects undertaken by Ethlyne J. Seligman for Germain Seligman or on her own behalf. Projects include the art of Jacques-Louis David, the cloisters of Chartreuse in Paris, a portrait of Henri II, and pre-Columbian art and culture. The subseries also contains a notebook entitled "Library Catalog," but it is not clear if the notebook refers to Seligman's personal library or to another collection. An incomplete copy of the volume L'Art du Dix-Huitième Siècle can also be found here.
    Arrangement is alphabetical by subject and chronological within folders. This series has not been scanned.
    - Chartreuse de Paris ou de Vouvert, Copy of Volume, undated, (not scanned) (Box 457, Folder 1)
    - Chartreuse de Paris Project: Correspondence, 1965-1979, (not scanned) (Box 457, Folder 2)
    - Chartreuse de Paris Project: Research Material, 1957-1964, undated, (not scanned) (Box 457, Folder 3)
    - Chartreuse de Paris Project: Research Notes, 1967, undated, (not scanned) (Box 457, Folder 4)
    - Chartreuse de Paris Project: Photographs of Works of Art, undated, (not scanned) (Box 457, Folder 5)
    - J. L. David Project: Notes, undated, (not scanned) (Box 457, Folder 6)
    - J. L. David Project: Notes, Museums, undated, (not scanned) (Box 457, Folder 7)
    - J. L. David Project: Notes, Private Collectors, undated, (not scanned) (Box 457, Folder 8)
    - Portrait of Henry II Project: Research Material, 1971-1973, undated, (not scanned) (Box 458, Folder 1)
    - Portrait of Henry II Project: Research Notes, 1970-1971, undated, (not scanned) (Box 458, Folder 2)
    - Pre-Columbian Art and Culture: Notebook and Miscellany, 1936, 1946, undated, (not scanned) (Box 458, Folder 3)
    - Pre-Columbian Art and Culture: Postcards, undated, (not scanned) (Box 458, Folder 4)
    - Library Catalog Notebook, undated, (not scanned) (Box 459, Folder 1)
    - L'Art du Dix-Huitième Siècle, Incomplete Copy of Publication, 1882, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 459, Folder 2-3)